Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Metcalfe, Theophilus (fl. ). Metcalf's [sic] Short-Hand corrected & improved by Dr. I.W.. **Perhaps a copy of a printed edition., 1649 1763 ca. 1810.; 170/432; Manuscript, 29 leaves.
  - Metcalfe, Theophilus (fl. 1649). Metcalf's [sic] Short-Hand improved by Dr. I. Watts (?)., ca. 1750; 170/433; Manuscript, 22 leaves.
  - Cunliffe Library. Catalogue of the Cunliffe Library. **The Library was auctioned by Sotheby's in May 1946., ca. 1885; *170/434; Manuscript, 183 leaves.
  - Padua. Università. In Christi nomine amen (Padua, ). **Doctoral diploma issued to Alexander Mantuanus, with skillful miniature painting in oils., 1681; 170/435; Manuscript, 4 leaves.
  - Huband, W. Essays on English Orthography ... to which is annexed an orthographical vocabulary (Dublin, )., ca. 1810; 170/436; Manuscript, 85 leaves, and interleaved by the author's son, with copious notes and revisions.
  - Lilford, Thomas Powys, 2nd baron (1775-1825). Catalogue of the Lilford Library (Oundle, Peterborough, )., ca. 1815-1840; *170/437; Manuscript, 49 leaves.
    See also: 170/421 and 170/423.
  - Scott, Christopher. De natura et gratia (Rome?, ). **Lectures on theology written in English., ca. 1850; 170/438; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - [Foxe, John (1516-1587)]. The Lives of the English Martyrs epitomized. **Paraphrase of Foxe's Actes and Monuments., ca. 1750; 170/439; Manuscript, 317 leaves.
  - Earl, Guy Chaffee (1861-1935). Recollections (Oakland, )., 1925; *170/440; Carbon typescript, 231 leaves.
  - Weston, James. Mr. James Weston's New Method of Short Hand., 1744; 170/441; Manuscript, 75 leaves.
  - Domenico Calvalca. Volgarizzamento dei Dialogih de s. Gregorio Magno. Translated from Latin into Italian by Domenico Cavalca (Venice? s. XV ex.)., 170/442; Manuscript, 120 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, pp.75-77.
  - Chinese-Latin Dictionary. Chinarum librum litteracaracter., ca. 1725; 170/443; Manuscript rice paper. 597 leaves.
  - Rome (City). Museo Capitolino. Copy drawings from the Statues, Busts & Relics in the Capitol at Rome ()., 1822; *170/444; Original drawings 228 leaves.
  - Dong-Kook-Yu-Ji-Do (Korea ). **Copy of an 18th century map of Korea. The original seems to have been lost., 1889; *170/445; Manuscript, 8 folding maps.
    See also: N.J.W. Thrower, Imago Mundi 21, 1967.
  - Reminiscences of Inyo County, ca. 1885-1954 (Los Angeles, 1952-1954). **Transcripts of 16 interviews with pioneer Inyo County residents., 170/446; Typescript, 389 leaves.
  - Reserved for Inglis manuscripts., 170/447
  - Robinson, William Heath (1872-1944). Illustrations for The Child's Arabian Nights (England, ). **The work itself was published in 1906., ca. 1905; 49 original drawings, 12 are water-coloured. 88 leaves.
  - Holloway, Ernest Ferrers. The New Koran, or The Truth as I See It (London ). **An attempt to synthesize the world's various religions. Inscribed An den Reichs-kanzler [Adolf Hitler] mit Grüssen von E.F. Holloway. Reputed to have been found in Hitler's library., 1938-1939; 170/449; Manuscript, 135 leaves.
  - [Scargill, William Pitt (1787-1836).] The Usurer's Daughter. (England, ). **Original manuscript with corrections. The work itself was published in 1832., ca. 1830; 170/450; Manuscript, 420pp.
  - Mohn, Einar (b. 1906). Teamster Leader (San Francisco, ). **Transcript of a tape recorded interview., 1970; 170/451; Typescript (carbon). 764 leaves.
  - Hedley, Anthony. Commonplace Books (Hexham, North-umberland, ). **Hedley was a clergyman at Kirk Whelpington, Hexham. These volumes contain copies of his letters; copies of burial and other records; extracts from books; and notes of antiquarian interest. A list of contents appears at vol.3, p.428., ca. 1808-1834; *170/452; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - The Gossip. no.62-69 (Lincoln, England, ). **A literary periodical issued by a group of friends for their own amusement. Includes a mock Gothic novel, The Haunted Priory, a Legendary Fragment., April 5-May 30, 1820 1819; 170/453; Manuscript, 129 leaves, illustrated by watercolour drawings.
  - Schaertlin, Alberto Muller. The Yellow Count, with the Japanese Check of 138 Million Yen (New York, ). **An account of a swindle based on fraudulent papers from the Russo-Japanese War. Apparently unpublished., 1935; Typescript with holograph corrections.
  - [Guglielmi, Pietro Carlo (ca. 1763-1817). La donna di più caratteri. Libretto by Giuseppe Palomba]. **An opera, in two acts, published by Marsigli-Rossi, Bologna, ca. 1805 1806.; 170/455; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - [Hymn Book, (American, ).] Manuscript music. **Ebenezer Alden's property. 1804. A few popular songs appear at the end. Scorched by fire., ca. 1800; 170/456; Manuscript, 91 leaves.
  - [Song Book (American, )]. **Ex libris: Ebenezer Alden. Scorched by fire., ca. 1800; 170/457; Manuscript, 100pp.
  - [Song (American, )]. **Ex libris: Alden. Includes's Ariel's song from Shakespeare (p.36)., ca. 1800; 170/458; Manuscript, 56pp. Scorched by fire.
  - 1-3. Patten-Saunders, W.H., Captain. Black and Gold; or, The Don! the Don! A Tale of the Circassian War (England, ). **Published in, ca. 1864 1864.; *170/459 v; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - [Hymn and Song Book (American, )]., ca. 1825; 170/460; Manuscript, 98pp.
  - Jesuits. Paraguay. [Documents concerning the Investigation of the Dispute between Bishop Bernardino de Cardenas and the Jesuits of Paraguay]). Phillipps Manuscript no.16172, 17405., ca. 1664-1665; *170/461; Manuscripts, 130 leaves.
  - Mexico. Tesoreía. Account book for the year 1715, under the charge of Don Juan Antonio Vasquez (Mexico City[?], )., 1715-1716; *170/462; Manuscript, 270 leaves.
  - Vincent, Sir Francis, 10th bart. (1803-1880). Katharine's Son (England, ). **A novel in 3 vol., with copious additions and corrections. Apparently unpublished., ca. 1864; 170/463; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - [St John, Isabella, Lady.] The Legacy (England, ). **Four stories, published by Richard Bentley as Mrs Cleveland, and the St. Clairs'., ca. 1835; 170/464; Defective manuscript.
  - England. Politicial History. Collection of Twelve Manuscripts and one printed broadside concerning treaties and foreign relations between England and various European countries). **Apparently, official documents., ca. 1502-1659; *170/465
  - Bible. Manuscripts, Armenian. N.T. ** The Minassian Codex., 170/466
  - Armenian manuscript. **Silver cover., 170/467
  - Ward, John. A Treatise of Hydrostaticks (England, ). **Also on Astronomy., 1763; 170/468; Manuscript, 126 leaves.
  - Santa Maria Buenavista. Records of the Haciendas Santa Maria Buenavista and San Geronimo in Central Mexico (Mexico, )., ca. 1500-1700; *170/469; Manuscript, 2 vol. (417 leaves).
  - Spain. Archivo general de Indias, Seville. Simancas eclesiastico audiencia de Charcas. Cartas y espedientes del Cabildo Eclesiatico de Charcas vistos en el Cosejo. Ano 1566 à 1699 (Seville[?], ). Transcript of arguments concerning the division of the Spanish colonial area of Charcas (Bolivia and parts of Peru, Argentina, Chile, and Paraguay). Lists of Spanish and Indian population etc., ca. 1850; *170/470; Manuscript, 128 leaves.
  - Yale University. Yale catalogus senatus 1862 and lectures (New Haven, ). Nine pamphlets relating to Yale courses and students. The final section consists of Outlines of Lectures, and is annotated., 1856-1863; 170/471; 1 vol.
  - Tehauacan, Mexico. [Book of Accounts (Tehuacan, )]. **Text chiefly in Náhuatl., 1642-1649; *170/472; Manuscript, 187pp.
  - Bray, Anna Eliza (Kempe) Stothard (1790-1883). Trials of Domestic Life (London: Henry Colburn, ). **Copious holograph revisions, deletions and additions for reprint., 1848; 170/473; 3 vol.
  - Curtis, Edward Sheriff (1868-1952). Index of Curtis Negatives. **Numerical index to a privately held archive of negatives made by Curtis. Included are the negatives of Indians of North America., *170/474; Photocopies. 3 vol.
  - François I, King of France (1494-1547). Letters (1523-1524). **Written by several scribes, signed by Francis I, the letters concern Giovanni da Verrazzano's voyage of discovery to the New World in 1524. Letters 1-5 are addressed to M. de Chillon; letter 6 to a Vice Admiral (unidentified)., *170/475; Manuscript, 6 items.
  - [Meeks, Bernard M.] [Catalogue of Children's Books collected by Meeks (Arlington, Virginia, )]., ca. 1955; 170/476; **Typescript, 217 leaves. **About 1500 books at UCLA.
  - Reserved for Hungarian Manuscripts., 170/477
  - Rose, Florence (d. 1969). A Catalogue of the Margaret Sanger Papers, 1914-1939, in the Library of Congress. **Preliminary rough draft., 170/478; Typescript (Ozalid reproduction) 202 leaves.
  - O'Melveny, Henry William (1859-1941). Recollections (Los Angeles, ). **Remarks of senior partner of the law firm O'Melveny & Myers., 1939; 170/479; Typescript (photographic reproduction). 85 leaves.
  - Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, Los Angeles. Brochure on the painting A Hampshire Homestead by William Shayer, senior. (Los Angeles, )., 1933?; *170/480; Typescript, 15 leaves, illustrations.
  - California. Division of Highways. District VII. Route 166 between Long Beach Freeway and Atlantic Blvd (Los Angeles, ). **Transcript of public meeting held, 1959 December 1, 1959.; 170/481; 45pp., maps. With carbon copies of related material.
  - Rogers, Samuel (1763-1855). Italy, a Poem (London, )., 1835; 170/482; **Fore-edge painting of a waterfront cottage. Prize binding, 1839.
  - Bowles, William Lisle (1762-1850). Poems, vol. II (London, )., 1803; 170/483; **Fore-edge Painting of ships.
  - Los Angeles. Department of Water and Power. Record of proceedings relating to the authorization, issuance, execution, sale and delivery of $22,775,000, Department of Water and Power of the City of Los Angeles, electric plant refunding revenue bonds, issue of 1943. vol.2., 1943-1946; 170/484; Documents. 25 leaves.
  - Los Angeles. Department of Water and Power. Record of proceedings relating to the authorization, issuance, execution, sale and delivery of $15,000,000, Department of Water and Power of the City of Los Angeles, electric plant refunding revenue bonds, issue of 1944., 170/454; Documents. 97 leaves.
  - Middleton, Robert E. The Battle of Beau Coudray (Death Valley): an Eyewitness account., January 1948; 170/486; Typescript (carbon) 28 leaves.
  - California. Division of Highways. District VII. Project report on the Santa Ana Parkway, a state highway in Los Angeles, Anaheim and Santa Ana between Aliso Street, Los Angeles and First Street, Santa Ana (Los Angeles, )., 1948; 170/487; Text of report, 96pp.
  - California. Division of Highways. District VII. Project report for replacement of bridge and approaches ... at Rio Hondo Channel ... in Los Angeles County (Los Angeles, )., 1949; 170/488; Carbon Typescript of report, 35pp.
  - Hoover, John Edgar (1895-1972). Papers (Washington, D.C. ). Papers, reports and lectures delivered by Hoover. These copies were sent to Leon Lambert, Chief of Provincial Police, Quebec., circa. 1934-1937; 170/489; Autograph letter signed; Mimeographs 3 vol. (528 leaves); illustrations. 16 letters from Hoover bound in.
  - Southern California Edison Company. 800,000 shares of common stock. On incorporation, registration of S.E.C., 1952; *170/490; Carbon Typescript.
  - Gebelin, François (b. 1884). Les chateaux de la renaissance (Paris, ). Ex libris: Charles Boyer., ca. 1927; *170/491; **Elaborately bound by Richert in full green morocco, upper cover inlaid in white touched with purple and black, within a gold rule; spine inlaid in brown.
  - Doré, Robert (b. 1890). L'art en Provence (Paris, ). Ex libris: Charles Boyer., ca. 1930; *170/492; **Elaborately bound by Richert.
  - Huard, Georges (b. 1887). L'art en Normandie (Paris ). Ex libris: Charles Boyer, ca. 1928; *170/493; **Elaborately bound by Richert.
  - [Harris, Robert E.G.] The Many Faces of Spain (Madrid, ). **Articles in Spanish from the journal <Blanco y Negro., 1974; *170/494; Typescript English translations.
    See also: no.170/505.
  - Treat, Clara L. Trip to Boulder Dam., June 25, 1935; 170/495; Typescript, 27pp.
  - Extraits bibliographiques, ou recueil des auteurs les plus estimés dans divers genres: avec quelque détail de leurs ouvrages. Utile à ceux qui veulent former une bibliothèque choisie (). **Ex libris: Charles Boyer., 1799; 170/496; Manuscript, 187pp.
  - Hugo, Mme Adele (Foucher) (1806-1868). Victor Hugo raconté par un témoin de sa vie (Paris, ). **With letters from Hugo and F.A. Harel (1790-1846). Ex libris: Charles Boyer., 1863; 170/497; Extra-illustrated. 2 vol.
  - [Troupes françaises (Paris, 181-?). **107 plates removed from various editions of the Troupes françaises, uniforms of the French Army during the Napoleonic period. Ex libris: Charles Boyer., 170/498; 2 vol.
  - [Keepsake Album (England? 1873-1877). **Messages addressed to Jenny from her classmates., 170/499; Manuscript, 48pp.
  - vol.1-2. Bethune, Joseph-Maximilian-Guislain, Marquis de (1705-1789), compiler. Receuil [sic] de chansons choisies. **Songs., ca. 1750; 170/500; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Recueil de morceaux concernant soit l'histoire soit la littérature (France, 1782). **Contains e.g. life of Marie-Theresa etc. Ex libris: Charles Boyer., 170/501; Manuscript, 40 leaves.
  - Janss Investment Company. Tract Book of Westwood Village and Franklin Avenue Square (Los Angeles, )., ca. 1937; *170/502; Typescript and maps. 25 leaves.
  - Thorne, Marco G. The Diary of Levi Stowell., 1849; 170/503
  - Moore, Thomas (1779-1852). The Poetical Works (London, ). **Fore-edge painting of street scene with neo-classic building, carriages, and children playing with a dog. Ex libris: Lawrence Durrell., 1846; 170/504
  - [Harris, Robert E.G., ed.] The Monuments of Spain (Madrid, ).**Articles in Spanish with Typescript English translations of captions to illustrations., 1975; *170/505; 2 vol.
    See also: 170/494.
  - Cano y Nieto, Alonso (1711-1780). Nuevo aspecto de la topografia de Argel: su estado, fuerzas y govierno, comparado con el antiguo. **Account of a trip made to Algiers in 1768-1769 to ransom Spanish captives and to gather information on Algerian military and naval strength., ca. 1769; 170/506; Manuscript, 248pp.
  - Schneider, Walter Otto (1895-1962), compiler. Catalogs of Mr. Schneider's library and graphic arts collection (Los Angeles, ). Typescript (pasteup). **vol.1: Frans Masereel collection; vol.2: Miscellaneous books in the collection (willed to the UCLA Library)., ca. 1915-1962; 170/507; 2 vol.
  - Ranchos of Southern California (ca. 1834-1883)., **170/508; Manuscript, 86 maps in Spanish (390 × 560mm.).
    - Diseños: maps and plans of ranchos of Southern California, mostly within Los Angeles and Orange counties
  - Lermontov, Mikhail Iur'evrich (1814-1841). Izo dnia v den', izvlecheniia iz cochinenii Lermontova na kazhdyi den' goda. **Calendar of selections from the works of Lermontov used as a memory book. The compiler was Olga Konstantinovna, the granddaughter of Tsar Paul I., 1886; *170/509; 1 vol.
  - Platt & Platt. Los Angeles City Business & Speculative District (Los Angeles, ). **Holograph maps of tracts of downtown Los Angeles., 1902; 170/510; 102 leaves.
  - Keys, James M. The Spanish Missions of California and their Influence Today (Portland, ). **Thesis., 1949; Carbon Typescript 169+ leaves.
  - Shaw, George Bernard (1856-1950). Ellen Terry and Bernard Shaw: their Correspondence. Preface only (Edinburgh, ). **Proof copy sent by Shaw to Edward Gordon Craig. Accompanied by two manuscripts written by Craig., 1929; 51 leaves.
  - Ordenanzas del Baratillo de Mexico dada per via de exortazion o consejo a sus dotores. Compuestas por Don Pedro Anselmo Chreslos Jache (). **Analysis of the social and economic state of Mexico. Formerly Phillipps Manuscript no.21332., ca. 1800; 170/513; Manuscript. 155 leaves.
  - Varios papeles jocoserios intitulados El Duende. Que salieron en diferentes Jeuves, de los anos 1735 y 1736. Segunda parte de la obra del Duende Critico de Palazio. **Satirical periodical, mostly in verse, directed principally against the minister Patino, and circulated only in manuscript copies during the 18th century., 170/514; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Clark, William Johnson (1918-1976)/Hartzell, James S. Author/Title Index for Adventure Magazine (Los Angeles, )., ca. 1971; 170/515; Photocopy, with manuscript additions. 2 vol.
  - Clark, William Johnson (1918-1976). Author/Title Index for Adventure Magazine (compiled by William J. Clark and James S. Hartzell (Los Angeles, )., ca. 1970; 170/515; Photocopy. 2 vol. with typescript additions.
  - Clark, William Johnson (1918-1976). Author/Title Index for Blue Book Magazine (Los Angeles, )., ca. 1970; 170/516; Photocopy. 1 vol.
  - Clark, William Johnson (1918-1976). Author/Title Index for Western Story Magazine (Los Angeles, )., 1970; 170/517; Photocopy. 1 vol.
  - Neumann, Robert G. Afghanistan: Experiment in Democracy., 1977; 170/518; Oral History transcript.
  - Neumann, Robert G. Morocco & the Sahara., 1977; 170/519; **Oral History Transcript.
  - Socii Bollandiani. Bibliotheca hagiographica Latina antiquae et mediae aetatis (Bruxelles, ). **Interleaved, copiously annotated by John M. Howe, UCLA Department of History, 1949 1976-1977.; 170/520; 4 vol.
    (Restricted).
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. Antiphonarium (Italy s. XV¹)., 170/521; Manuscript, 70 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, pp.77-78.
  - Hader, Berta (Hoerner). Rainbow's End (New York, ). **With an original watercolour on the half-title by Berta and Elmer Hader, inscribed to Frances Clarke Sayers., 1945; 170/522
  - Collins, Holdridge Ozro (b. 1844). Papers. **Mostly records received by Collins as General Historian of the General Society, Sons of the Revolution., 1903-1907; 170/523; Manuscript & printed. 1 vol.
  - Rasis. Liber Almansoris (fragment (Italy s. XIII²)., 170/524; Manuscript, 2 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, pp.78-79.
  - Hurtado de Mendoza, Diego (1503-1575). De la Guerra de Granada (Spain, s. XVI ex. or XVI-XVII). **Account of the war against the Moors. First published in, 1627.; 170/525; Manuscript, 130 leaves.
    See also: Ferrari, p.79.
  - Albert III and Leopold III, Dukes of Austria. Patent Letter in favour of Hermans von Landenberg (Neuenstadt, 12 May 1368)., 170/526; Manuscript.
    **See Ferrari, p.180.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. Missale and Liber censuum of the Church of Oker (Germany [Oker], s. XII-XVI)., *170/527; Manuscript, 17 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, pp.79-81.
  - Vacant., 170/528
  - Commonplace Book (England, s. XVI third quarter). **Notes on philosophy in Greek and Latin in dictionary form; geographical names; excerpts from Pausanias; notes on chronology, astrology, Latin-Greek dictionary from A to Ingratus; notes in Italian on geometry; list of Kings of England; laws of Anglo-Saxon Kings, in Latin; Laws of William the Conqueror, in Anglo-Norman and Latin; copies of documents in Anglo-Saxon. Ex libris: Laurence Nowell (d. 1576); William Lambarde (1536-1601), Matthew Parker, Archbishop of Canterbury (1504-1575)., 170/529; Manuscript, on paper. 276 leaves.
    See also: Ferrari, pp.81-82.
  - Weidenmann, Jacob (1829-01893). Contents of a scrapbook. **Comprises 92 original drawings of building designs by Weidenmann, landscape architect, including some for specific American gardens., 1871-1894; **170/530; Manuscript and printed. 111 items.
  - Caballero y Góngora, Antonio, Cardinal (1723-1796). Relación del estado del Nuevo Reyno de Granada; que hace el Arsobispo obispo de Cordova, a su successor el excelentisimo senor Don Francisco Guyl de Lemos ano de 1789. **Caballero y Góngora was Viceroy of New Granada, i.e. Colombia, Ecuador and Venezuela, from 1782 to 1788., ca. 1789; 170/531; Manuscript, 207 leaves.
    See also: J.M. Perez Ayala's Antonio Caballero y Góongora (Bogota, 1951) pp.201-03, 297-392.
  - Commonplace book (English, )., ca. 1828; 170/532; **Includes water-colour drawings and pencil sketches.
  - Davey, Norman (b. 1888). The Pilgrim of a Smile. **Mostly published, 1921., ca. 1921; *170/533; Manuscript, 360 leaves.
  - Banks, Isabella (Varley) (1821-1897). The Slowly Grinding Mills (London, )., 1893; 170/534; 3 vol. Holograph revisions in vol.2-3.
  - Unger, Frank. It hath been said. **Collection of literary quotations lettered and decorated by Unger., 1908; 170/535; Illuminated Manuscript.
  - Webb, Dorothy E. (Haldeman). Biography of Harry Marston Haldeman (Beverly Hills, ?)., 1976; 170/536; Photocopy Typescript.
  - Cohen & Levy, Vallecito, California (Loan Receipt Book., April 19, 1859-April 9, 1867; 170/537; Manuscript, 1 vol.
  - San Francisco. St. Luke's Hospital. Articles of Incorporation and By Laws of the St. Luke's Hospital, San Francisco., November 30, 1885-October 18, 1900; 170/538; Manuscript, 192pp.
  - Brooks & Rouleau, searchers of titles, San Francisco. Abstract of title to [a] portion of block no.1, western addition as shown by the various records in the City and County of San Francisco., April 1866; *170/539; Document signed. 100pp.
  - Joseph & E.B. Clement, examiners of titles to real estate, San Francisco. Abstract of title to lot on Pacific St. (50 vara lot no.115) in the city and county of San Francisco, 1892., *170/540; Document. 173 leaves.
  - Amesti, José. Cuaderno de cuentas dela case del J(os)é Amesti del año de 1840 [i.e. 1839] a 1850. **Account book of a prominent merchant of Monterey, California., 128pp.
  - Augustinus, Aurelius, Saint, Bp of Hippo. Liber soliloquiorum. Netherlands, s. XV in., 170/542; Parchment 115 leaves.
  - [Accounts of famous murders in 16th century Italy] (Padua? ). **Murders of Vittoria Accoramboni Orsini, the Marchese de Massimi, and the Duchess of Paliano. Orsini's murder inspired John Webster's play, The White Devil. Phillipps Manuscript no.2433., ca. 1600; 170/543; Manuscript, 60 leaves.
  - [Atlas and British History Book] (England, ). **Contains a map of the world in two hemispheres and a double-page map of England and Wales., ca. 1783; 170/544; Manuscript, 45 leaves.
  - Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Lear (English, 19th century), annotated by George MacDonald (1824-1905)., 170/545; Printed (pp.433-544) and manuscript.
  - Petrarca, Francesco, 1304-1374. Rime. (Italy [Florence?], s. XIV/XV in. **Includes Ariosto's Orlando furioso XIV, XCII 1-6, 1. 97. Phillipps Manuscript no.4044., 170/546; Manuscript, on parchment. 100 leaves.
  - Petrarca, Francesco, 1304-1374. Trionfi etc. (Italy, ). **Includes the oldest dated manuscript of the life of Petrarch. Ex libris: Minocci family of Siena, s. XV; T. Phillipps., 1426; 170/547; Manuscript, on paper. 162 leaves.
  - Howell, William E. Real Estate Tract Directory and Land Purchasers' Guide to Los Angeles County. (Los Angeles, )., 1888; 170/548; 278pp. & interleaving.
  - Cooke, C., firm, publishers, London. Proof prints of illustrations for Cooke's Pocket edition of the original and complete works of select poets, classics, and novels (London, )., 1795-1804; 170/549
  - Perrote, Luis. Judgment concerning the hidalguia of Luis Perrote (Spain, )., 1590; 170/550; Parchment 28 leaves.
    **See Ferrari.
  - Cicero, Marcus Tullius. De amicitia (beginning only). (Italy s. XV/XVI)., 170/551; Paper. Manuscript, one quire of ten leaves.
  - Rabbi Samuel, Sermones etc., (Poland [Poznan], ). **Written by Johannes Faber of Poznan in 1405., *170/552; Manuscript, on paper. 166 leaves.
  - Fioretto novello estratto della Bibbia (Venice, )., 1447; 170/553; Manuscript, 112 leaves.
  - Woolf, Virginia (Stephen) (1882-1941). Mrs. Dalloway. London, Hogarth Press, **Inscribed to Jacques Raverat, 1925. February 6, 1925.; 170/554; First proof with holograph corrections.
  - Vacant., 170/555
  - Heath, Charles (1785-1848). [Engravings] (London, 1823-1825). **Accompanied by letter from heath to Dawson Turner, May 29, 1823.; *170/556; 96 leaves.